Following the Board of Adjustments
meeting for June 23rd. Do I have that
date right?
>> But
>> June 25th, um, 2026. Uh, staff, please
call roll.
>> Charity Campfield.
Curtis Clayball.
Linda Burt.
>> Here.
>> Michael O'Donnell.
>> Aaron Labounty.
Dustin Brown.
>> Here.
>> Chair, you have a quorum.
>> Great.
Um, with this being an emergency
meeting, we can only read the item item
A into the record. Is that Am I Am I on
the right page with that, Aaron?
>> Um, I actually do not know. I I think
that is what we're supposed to do.
>> Yeah, let's give that a go.
>> You you're going to put the agenda at
the next for the
>> Right, we we
>> All we do is the one item.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
Then, uh, staff, please read the item
in.
>> Item A, request PUDC-26-120, conditional
use request for entertainment,
amusement, recreation, other within the
CB zone, located at 3307 Nationway. The
agent is Amber Cornwell, and the case
planner is Morgan Dennis.
>> Thank you. Please proceed.
>> Um, can you guys hear me?
>> Yeah, what I would like to do is could I
have your name, and I'm going to swear
you in for the Board of Adjustments
meeting?
>> Uh, it's Morgan Dennis, Planning and
Development.
>> Oh, sorry sorry, Morgan. Oh, go ahead,
please.
>> You're you're good. I
You're good. Sorry I can't be in today.
Um,
uh, so I'll go ahead and give the staff
report.
Um, this is a conditional use request
for entertainment, amusement,
recreation, other at 3307 Nationway.
The parcel is located in the CB
community business zone with surrounding
zoning being CB and MR medium density
zoning.
The future land use use map designates
this area as community business and
urban residential.
The intent of the CB zone is for uses
that may serve a number of residential
neighborhoods in meeting daily needs,
discretionary needs, or other business
functions.
Entertainment, amusement, recreation, or
other other falls within the intent of
the CB zone as a component of other
business functions.
The proposed use at the location is for
a gaming parlor / HHR establishment,
historical horse racing establishment.
The previous site was
used for a bar. The previous use for the
site was a bar.
The site is currently
The [clears throat] site currently has
an existing building on the parcel that
will need to go through a site plan
process for a change of use if approved.
The site plan will need to meet all of
the standards for the community business
zone district. The operating
characteristics will be complimentary to
the existing surrounding area.
Business hours will be slightly reduced
from previous operating hours. The
proposed operating hours will
Uh
we'll skip that.
Uh while the number of trips is expected
to be no different from the previous
use, the time of the trips will be
affected by the
uh new operating hours. There are no
expected visible or audible impacts to
the property.
Um staff does want to make the board
aware of a text amendment that was
recently approved by the governing body
that will affect how gaming parlor
and the historical horse racing
establishments will be pro- processed
within city limits. Approval of gaming
parlors and historical horse racing
establishments will have to go through
the governing body for approval through
resolution
rather than come to the board of
adjustments for approval of a
conditional use.
Um this would require all existing
gaming parlors and HHR establishments to
seek re-approval through the governing
body before December 31st, 2027.
Um I don't know if Charles has wandered
in yet. Um he wrote the text amendment
and he can explain further. If not, I do
know a little bit more and I can expand
on that.
Oh, hey Charles.
>> I have. I can go ahead and provide some
details on that.
>> Okay.
>> Recently approved was a text amendment
that effectively changes the approval
body from the board of adjustment to the
city council through a special use
permit process. With that text
amendment, we made several changes to
the special use criteria to make it
one-size-fits-all, so it's not only for
uh enter- like these entertainment type
of uses, but also could be incorporated
other uses that need uh special use
approval. For example, a lot of like a
lot of communities use adult-oriented
businesses. Some other ones use other
establishments that could be subject to
those um extra review steps. Um this
would effectively put that decision on
the elected instead of the appointed. Um
so they can uh deal with that on
political standpoint and then they can
also review that at the same time as
they review the state license review.
Um
it's our understanding that this
application came in um not to beat the
deadline,
um but it was um because
the submittal date for the next gaming
commission date is tomorrow, the 30th,
um to get on the August agenda. So, if
they could have waited, they would have
waited, but they can't wait.
That uh new tax amendment will require
that all uh approved um facilities of
this type will have to reapply
um and have approval by the governing
body by December 31st of 2027.
Um
uh I've been
I I will be working with the State
Gaming Commission to make sure there
aren't any additional steps that may be
necessary between now and the August
meeting or post their August meeting to
make sure that we're
uh
both navigating this transitional period
smoothly.
>> Thank you.
>> Mhm. All right. Um
with this uh staff does recommend
approval as the does meet all the review
criteria.
So.
>> Okay. Thank you. Any questions for
staff?
All right. Then um with that said, if
the applicant would like to say
anything, please come forward.
And please state your name and your
address.
>> Sure. Thank you so much. Tracy Leacock.
I serve as general counsel to both
Wyoming Downs and 307 horse racing. My
address is 1720 Carey Avenue, Suite 601,
Cheyenne, Wyoming 82001.
Um the staff did give an action Oh,
excuse me.
>> Uh do you swear to tell the truth and
the whole truth in the matter before the
Board of Adjustments?
>> I do.
>> All right. Great. Please go ahead.
>> Thank you.
Um the staff did adequately um state
what the status of the current laws
were. Sort of in this transition period.
Um we have decided we will go back to
the city for the resolution prior to
going uh back to the commission um based
on the attorney general's uh opinion
that when we go in front of the
commission, which the next meeting is
August 15th, we will be required to um
comply with all current law. Um however,
we have started this process. We thought
we wanted to try to get it through it
just in case the city's um current
ordinance didn't go through. We did work
with uh city planning and the city
council um with the new ordinance. We
think it's going to work really well. Uh
this uh current location operates as
Cadillac uh Ranch Bar. Uh that's the
current uh usage, and we would request
that uh the Board of Adjustments approve
our conditional use. Happy to answer any
questions.
>> Yes, thank you. Any questions for the
applicant?
Great.
All right. Then with that, I'll ask if
anyone else representing um or here on
behalf of the public would like to make
comment.
With that, we'll close public comment,
and the chair will entertain a motion.
>> Mr. Chairman,
I move to approve a conditional use
request for the use of entertainment,
amusement, recreation  other at
3307 Nation Way as presented by the
applicant as the application meets all
review criteria outlined in UDC section
2.2.4.D
as in dog.
>> And do we have a second?
>> I can.
>> All right.
That said, any any further discussion?
All right. Staff, please call roll.
>> Linda Burt?
>> Yes.
>> Charity Campfield?
>> No.
>> Michael O'Donnell?
>> I.
>> Dustin Brown?
>> Yes.
>> Chair, the motion passes.
>> Thank you.
All right. And with that, I'll I'll pass
over to staff for any other any other
business and we'll Oh, Sorry.
>> we we need to Can we go to executive
session?
Uh I I make a motion to go to exec
to executive session to receive legal
advice on the vote that just occurred.
>> Yes.
>> And that means we need to have everybody
vacate the room.
>> As an option, you may be
>> done.
>> Go for it.
As you may be able to walk to the next
room to your right over there's a door.
That room should be available where you
can bump into there for executive
session and then come back to the doc.
>> It's okay if they go out in the hallway.
But I would like all the
board members to be able to hear us.
>> Oh, yes. Um okay. I will mute Well,
Yeah.
>> I I I think we're all tracking. Uh give
us give us just a second, Charles.
>> Okay.
Mr. Chairman,
>> Yes.
>> let's turn this over to council first.
>> Yeah.
>> We need
>> of the board,
>> Yes.
>> not a majority of the board members
present.
>> We need four yeses.
>> votes
>> in order to pass the the conditional
use. The problem we've got with one no
vote
and the motion failing,
the basis for a no vote has to be that
the applicant meets none of the
criteria. Does not not not It fails
every single test.
All of them.
And that is not the case.
>> Well,
I I want to be I want to be careful and
and defer to you because if if we if we
go into the criteria, I think we need to
bring everybody back in to discuss the
criteria yes. But if we're talking
process, I think we're we're good to
talk process with you, right?
>> Well, I guess we need to know the reason
why the nay vote was made.
>> Yes.
And that
that's probably beyond the scope of
executive session.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh
so
we do need four eye votes to pass this.
And if we don't pass it, we have to make
a record
of why it didn't pass, and that record
has to satisfy
the
our our role.
>> UDC, yes. And it's And it's got to go
through each criteria and say why it
doesn't qualify.
>> Yes.
Charity, are you tracking that?
>> I am.
>> Okay.
>> Okay, then let's I move to adjourn
executive session and go back into open
session.
>> Agreed.
>> Mr. Chairman, when you reconvene us, I
have a point of order to raise.
>> Yes.
With that said, I reconvene reconvene
the Board of Adjustments.
>> Mr. Chairman, point of order on the vote
that was just taken. The because there
are only four members of the board in
attendance tonight, in order to pass any
item before the board, it requires a
vote of all four present in the positive
for the motion.
If the motion fails
our UDC requirements uh require that it
be established in the record so that
Jeffrey can draw up an order
that I did that goes through each of the
is it seven criteria?
Eight criteria and identifies why
each criteria fails.
>> With that said, I would like to open up
for the board to consider further public
comment or further comment from the
board. Um anyone that would like to say
anything, please go ahead.
>> Morgan, can you
go point by point for each criteria and
why this project meets the criteria?
>> Why it does not meet.
>> Yes, correct.
>> Yes.
Or
a member of the prevailing
voting block
on the original motion can bring a
motion to reconsider.
If
that is
the desire of the chair and the board.
And and Mr. Chairman, if I might make a
comment.
>> Yes, please.
>> Um
this is one of those awkward things
where there are strong strong feelings
about gaming and gambling and horse
racing in this community.
The problem is we are not the body that
is empowered to make the political
decision.
The Board of Adjustment has a limited
scope under the the UDC
and
we can only deny an application for a
conditional use if all eight
criteria fail.
>> Yes, um I your point is taken and I
believe, you know, that was that was
clearly identified in our training as we
came on to the board is that if we do
not concur that items meet criteria,
that indication has to be represented by
the member that believes that. So, with
that, the chair will either
at will
entertain further discussion or a
new motion.
>> A motion to reconsider
>> I'm sorry.
>> It depending on
uh Ms. Campfield's response, I'll be
prepared to bring a motion to
reconsider.
But, we need to hear from her first.
>> Yes.
>> How about I just bring the motion to
reconsider?
>> Okay.
>> Understood. Do we have a second?
>> Second.
>> I I yes, I second.
>> A second?
>> Yes.
>> All right. Um
So, so now I can I can call for roll.
>> Yes, now it's a vote on the motion to
reconsider.
>> Okay. Staff, please call roll.
>> Linda Burke.
>> Yes.
>> Charity Campfield.
>> Michael O'Donnell.
>> I.
>> Dustin Brown.
>> Yes.
>> Chair, the motion passes.
>> Thank you.
Okay.
>> Mr. Chair, I move to adjourn.
>> All right. And um we'll adjourn this
meeting of the Board of Adjustments for
June 25th, 2026. Thank you everyone for
being here, and our apologies again for
the need to reschedule.
>> Wait, I Sorry, one quick question.
>> Yes.
>> Was that Was that last motion the motion
to reconsider? Did we do a the actual
motion to reconsider?
>> Oh, oh, oh. Sorry, sorry, Charles. Thank
you for mentioning that. Yes.
>> I'm getting over an illness, but I'm
just double-checking that I heard was
hearing everything right. Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Thanks.
>> Y- Yeah, we've now agreed to reconsider.
>> Okay.
>> Now, we need to vote.
>> Okay. Let's please vote on the motion.
Staff, please call roll.
>> Dustin Brown.
>> Yes.
>> Michael O'Donnell?
>> I.
>> Charity Campfield?
>> Yes.
>> Linda Burke?
>> The motion passes.
>> Thank you. And again, the this Board of
Adjustments meeting is adjourned.